Kenneth D. Swegman Jr.

Software Engineering

Pittsburgh, PA | Kenneth.swegman@gmail.com

Summary

Youthful, Passionate, and Excited Software Engineer with two prior internships developing web apps from front to backend, and being an admin in Azure, while using the cloud infrastructure on other development projects. Through course work and real-world experience, I have gained a fundamental skill in Computer Security and Networking.

Learned programming languages from all levels of computing. ARM v8, and C being my low-level, Java and C++ being mid-level, and JavaScript being high-level. Keen on taking on new and challenging opportunities in a Computer Security internship role.

Skills

Azure · PowerShell · Kali Linux
SQL Server · HTML/CSS · Power-BI
LaTex · Suricata · Wireshark
Metasploit · Logic Apps · Splunk
Nmap · Johnny · SET · SQL Map
Bash · John the Ripper · JSON
ARM Templates · tcpdump · Agile Dev
Awk · Linux Commands

Programming Languages

C · C++ · Python · SQL · ARM v8 · Java JavaScript · Rust

Web

Linkedin.com/in/kenny-swegman/ Kennethswegman.com github.com/swegboi

Experience

Duquesne Light Co.

Azure Engineering Intern, May 2019 – Aug 2019

- Developed front-end using Power-BI with backend using Azure Infrastructure (Using Azure SQL)
- Automated workflow for weather tracking system. Used Azure Logic Apps
- ❖ Weather Project built independently
- Dealt with Big Data, DB had over 450,000 rows of data
- Set up multiple servers, databases, and vms for other projects in the company

IT Intern, May 2017 – Aug 2017

Shadowed ReactJS Developers, and .Net Framework Developers

Education

La Roche University

B.S Computer Science (CS)
August 2015 – December 2019
Minor: Computer Security
January 2018 – December 2019

Activities

- Won 1st in Networking at AITP Conference for La Roche University in Fall 2017
- Competed in Steel Hacks 2018
- Radio Club President 2018 2019
- Film Club Vice President 2018 2019